Elrey C. Belmonti

Software Developer

Personal Info

Phone

267.325.2985

E-mail

elbelmonti@gmail.com

Portfolio

elrey.info

GitHub

https://github.com/ElreyB

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/elreyb/

Being a passionate people-person with over 10 years of experience as a professional dancer and in the hospitality industry; bringing tech and communities together is a dedication of mine. After a year and a half sabbatical, wire jewelry making and briefly attending Dev Bootcamp, I attended and graduated from Epicodus' 6 month program building web applications from scratch. Coding over a year and finishing my internship I am enthusiastic to bring my fullstack skills to your team/company.

Projects

Generator (Angular 5, Angular CLI, JavaScript, ES6 & ES7, Jasmine, Protractor, Nerdemer and Guppy math Libraries)

ChalkDoc internship working on an open source app given teachers the control to make customized, compelling assignments for their students.

Live Site: https://generator.chalkdoc.com/ **Github:** https://github.com/ElreyB/generator

Epic-Goose (HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap)

Conceptualized and served as team lead on a choose your own journey story application following the story of "Goblin Market".

Live site: https://elreyb.github.io/epic-goose/ **Github:** https://github.com/ElreyB/epic-goose

Vespolina Evento (Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Rspec)

Vespolina Evento is an app that makes it easier to request reservation for an event at Vespolina.

Live Site: https://peaceful-eyrie-37050.herokuapp.com/ **Github:** https://github.com/ElreyB/vespolina-evento

Experience

2018-01 -

Fullstack Intern

2018-02

ChalkDoc

- Identify and addressed tech debt
- · Organized daily goals
- Refactored existing code base using higher order functions & reduced total source lines of code by 60%
- · Ensured consistent and thorough documentation

2005-09 -

Manager, Host, Event Planner

2015-11

Hospitality Industry

- Full cycled event planning for parties up to 100 people
- Comfortable working with high-end clienteles, including celebrities and corporations
- Solidified relationships with repeat clients to deliver their party vision to reality
- Single-handedly created host manuals and trainings for four [high end] restaurants

2002-04 -

Choreographer

2015-10

Dance Companies In Philadelphia and Seattle Area

- Lead classes in modern dance and yoga
- Member of several dance companies that work internationally
- · Established a large network in the dance community

Education

2017-08 -

Epicodus

2018-02

Hands-on experience coding 8-hours a day building full-stack web applications with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails and Angular. Focusing on workflow, TDD, pair program, and writing maintainable, readable code.

2016-09 -

Dev Bootcamp

2017-05

Learn Ruby, Practical Object Oriented Design in Ruby, Git, Github, Algorithms and actively participated in Engineer Empathy lectures. Learning to learn quickly and efficiently while working on solo projects, pair programming, group projects, and volunteer coaching stress relieving techniques to peers.